<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NorCal Data Fest</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on NorCal Data Fest</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/unused/_sponsors_old/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/unused/_sponsors_old/</guid>
      <description>R Consortium Supporting the R community, the R Foundation and organzations developing, maintaining, and distributing R software. The central mission of the R Consortium is to work with and provide support to the R Foundation and to the key organizations developing, maintaining, distributing and using R software through the identification, development and implementation of infrastructure projects. Learn more about them at https://www.r-consortium.org/&#xD;Enloe Enloe Medical Center CFE The Center for Entrepreneurship is dedicated to providing the resources, inspiration, support, and mentorship to help inspired learners and doers develop ideas and launch valuable businesses.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2022 Sponsors</title>
      <link>/unused/_sponsors_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/unused/_sponsors_22/</guid>
      <description>Data Fest would not be able to happen without the support of the following people and organizations Please see our fundraising page for information on how you can support this high impact student activity.&#xA;Acknowledgements The Data Science Initiative at Chico State aims to be a hub of DS information and resources for campus and community. Our vision is to foster a data-empowered society working within a culture of open science.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2026 Sponsors</title>
      <link>/sponsors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/sponsors/</guid>
      <description>Data Fest would not be able to happen without the support of the following people and organizations Please see our fundraising page for information on how you can support this high impact student activity.&#xA;Terabye Sponsors ChicoSTART is an Accelerated by California Innovation Hub representing 20+ counties in the North State. We support and enrich Northern California’s entrepreneurial &amp; tech ecosystem by providing startups the resources they need to start, grow and thrive.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/faq/</guid>
      <description>What is DataFest? The American Statistical Association&amp;rsquo;s DataFest, founded at UCLA in 2011, is a 48-hour data analysis competition in which undergraduate students from various majors get to work in teams on large, complex, and real-world data. The data is kept secret until opening of the event on Friday evening and teams present their findings to a panel of judges on Sunday afternoon. Students explore, analyze, and visualize the data to discover insights.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About DataFest</title>
      <link>/unused/_about_unused/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/unused/_about_unused/</guid>
      <description>The American Statistical Association&amp;rsquo;s DataFest, founded at UCLA in 2011, is a 48-hour data analysis competition in which undergraduate students from various majors get to work in teams on large, complex, and real-world data. The data is kept secret until opening of the event on Friday evening and teams present their findings to a panel of judges on Sunday afternoon. Students explore, analyze, and visualize the data to discover insights. No prior knowledge of programming or data visualization is necessary!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coach &amp; Judge Information</title>
      <link>/coach_judge_info/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/coach_judge_info/</guid>
      <description>General Event Info All information regarding the event can be found at https://norcaldatafest.netlify.com/.&#xA;Location Throughout the weekend students will work in the event room on campus. There are many places to park around campus and downtown. Here is a link to an interactive map showing the cafe, and parking nearby.&#xA;Transportation &amp;amp; Parking There is metered parking (free on weekends) on Citrus Ave and Legion Ave. There is additional free street parking near the Gateway Science Museum.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coding and open data resources for participants</title>
      <link>/unused/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/unused/resources/</guid>
      <description>Computing and supplies We recommend that every member of the team bring a laptop, if possible. You might find it helpful to have a mix of PCs and Macs, since they have different strengths.&#xA;We recommend that you make sure beforehand that the software you will be using throughout the weekend is properly installed and running on your computer. You will be working with a large dataset so make sure that you have the space for it on your hard drive.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>Questions? For questions related to events held at Chico State, please contact Robin Donatello at datascience@csuchico.edu</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elm City Stories</title>
      <link>/blog/1/2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/1/2022/</guid>
      <description>Chico State Data Fest 2022 Recap On April 1-3rd, Chico State University hosted the ASA DataFest 2022. DataFest is an event hosted by the Chico State Data Initiative (DSI), organized by the Mathematics &amp;amp; Statistics department and Project DA-FANH&amp;rsquo;s project director Robin Donatello. Students were presented with undisclosed data on Friday and then worked through the weekend to gain the best insights into the confidential, real-world data sets. After long nights and early mornings, teams presented their findings to the experienced panel of judges for a chance at prizes and certificates.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Participant Info &amp; Guidelines</title>
      <link>/info_guide_chico/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/info_guide_chico/</guid>
      <description>Note: This document may be updated as the event approaches; any major updates will be clearly marked.&#xA;This is a long document, please take a moment to read over it carefully.&#xA;Location DataFest 2026 @ CSU, Chico will start with registration and end with awards ceremony in the the Behavioral and Social Sciences (BSS) building on Chico State Campus.&#xA;Transportation &amp;amp; Parking There is metered parking (free on weekends) on Citrus Ave and Legion Ave.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Participant Info &amp; Guidelines</title>
      <link>/info_guide_sac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/info_guide_sac/</guid>
      <description>Note: This document may be updated as the event approaches; any major updates will be clearly marked.&#xA;This is a long document, please take a moment to read over it carefully.&#xA;Sac State&amp;rsquo;s Data Science club - Their discord will be the official event discord on that weekend https://discord.gg/UmCx7bWXGS&#xA;Location The event will be held in the Carlsen Center for Innovation and Entrepreneurship in the Main Library on the Sacramento State campus.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Past Data Fest Events</title>
      <link>/_past_events/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/_past_events/</guid>
      <description>2023 - TBD 2022 - Elm City Stories The 2022 DataFest challenge came from the Play2Prevent lab at the Yale Center for Health &amp;amp; Learning Games in the Yale School of Medicine. DataFest participants analyzed data from Elm City Stories, an educational video game designed for middle and high school students. The goal of the game was to prevent negative health outcomes in young, at-risk adolescents by helping teens to increase perception of risk and to develop skills for predicting and understanding future consequences of actions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presentation Submissions</title>
      <link>/presentation_submissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/presentation_submissions/</guid>
      <description>Allowed file formats We very strongly recommend using PDF, Keynote, or PowerPoint. If using a web-based tool like GoogleDocs or Prezi, please export to PDF and upload the PDF as your submission. Note that you will not have time to log on/off to your account before your presentation. We don’t want to restrict your creativity but it is your responsibility to make sure that your presentation works seamlessly before the judging session begins.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Registration open until March 23, 2026</title>
      <link>/register/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/register/</guid>
      <description>All participants and volunteers must agree to abide by the following Code of Conduct.&#xA;Participants Register your team here&#xA;Undergraduate students from any higher education institution in the Northern California Region are eligible to participate. This is a team competition with between 2-5 students per team.&#xA;Looking for a team? Put your name down on this Team Formation sheet and join the 2026 NorCal DataFest Discord server to chat with other people who are looking for a team.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rugy</title>
      <link>/blog/1/2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/1/2019/</guid>
      <description>The data The data this year was provided by the Olympic Champion Canadian National Womens Rugby team. A complex set of four different datasets containing GPS tracking data during games, physical wellness surveys, and training workload. The data provider asked students to consider role of workload and fatigue in Rugby 7&amp;rsquo;s, a fast-paced very physically demanding sport that pushes the limits of athletic speed, endurance and toughness.&#xA;The people We had 48 students from 6 different schools register as 12 teams.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schedule of Events</title>
      <link>/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/schedule/</guid>
      <description>Team Forming Event! Don&amp;rsquo;t have a pre-formed team? Stay tuned for a team formation event one week prior to DataFest&#xA;Event Weekend Exact times are subject to change as needed.&#xA;Friday, April 10th, 2026 Welcome!&#xA;5pm - Registration sign in 5:30pm - Kickoff event with dinner Room open until midnight Saturday, April 11th, 2026 Carry on!&#xA;8am - Room opens with breakfast 12:30 pm - Lunch 6pm - Dinner Room open until midnight Sunday, April 12th, 2026 Wrap up!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supporting Data Fest in 3 ways</title>
      <link>/fundraising/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/fundraising/</guid>
      <description>Financial Contributions Participants are only allowed to work on this project while on site, so our biggest need is making sure they are well fed and caffeinated! Our fundraising goal for 2024 is $4000 which will be spent entirely on food, t-shirts, collaboration supplies such as notepads, whiteboard markers, portable whiteboards, student travel support and prizes for the winners.&#xA;All monetary donations are tax-deductible. Any remaining funds go directly towards supporting student centered Data Science education events such as the outreach and training sessions found on the Chico State DSI website.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
